<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks | Giuseppe De Laurentis</title>
    <link>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 15:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/media/icon_hud8124bf0cbf9cb4bbe62c81882a42a0c_277_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</title>
      <link>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytic Reconstruction of Two-Loop QCD Amplitudes</title>
      <link>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/sussexfeb2026/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/sussexfeb2026/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loop amplitudes are central to precision collider phenomenology, yet their computation remains challenging due to the complexity of intermediate steps. A powerful modern strategy is to bypass much of this complexity by performing numerical evaluations over finite fields and reconstructing analytic expressions from numerical data using number-theoretic and algebro-geometric techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will present a recent re-computation of the two-loop leading-colour amplitudes for the production of a heavy electroweak vector boson in association with two jets at hadron colliders (pp → Vjj). Compared to the previous state of the art, the new result achieves a three-order-of-magnitude reduction in size (from 1.4 GB to 1.9 MB) and reduces the required number of numerical samples from one million to fifty thousand. I will also briefly discuss applications to processes with massive external legs, including pp → tt̄H and HHH at one loop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will outline the core ingredients of this computation: a basis-change algorithm in the vector space of rational functions based on correlations among multivariate residues; numerical sampling in number fields with non-Archimedean metrics (finite fields and p-adic numbers); redundant spinor-helicity variables organised via polynomial quotient rings; and primary decompositions used to identify allowed multivariate partial fraction decompositions. Beyond enabling efficient phenomenological applications, these methods expose structural features that are expected to generalise to more complex QCD amplitudes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytic Reconstruction and Algebro-Geometric Structures in QCD: Two-Loop $pp \to Vjj$ &amp; One-Loop $pp \to t\bar{t}H$ &amp; $HHH$</title>
      <link>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/universe&#43;oct2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/universe&#43;oct2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loop amplitudes are central to precision collider phenomenology, yet their computation remains a major challenge due to the complexity of intermediate steps. A powerful modern strategy is to bypass this complexity through numerical evaluations over finite fields, followed by the reconstruction of the amplitudes’ analytic form from a set of numerical samples using number-theoretic and algebro-geometric techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will present the recent re-computation of the two-loop leading-colour amplitudes for the production of a heavy electroweak vector boson, $V=\{W^\pm,Z,\gamma^*\}$, in association with two light jets at hadron colliders ($pp\to Vjj$) (&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.10595&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;arXiv:2503.10595&lt;/a&gt;), including leptonic decays of the electroweak boson ($V\to \ell\bar{\ell}$). Compared to the previous state-of-the-art result (&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.07541&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;arXiv:2110.07541&lt;/a&gt;), the new approach achieves a three-order-of-magnitude reduction in size (1.4 GB to 1.9 MB), while also lowering the number of required numerical samples from one million to fifty thousand. To illustrate the applicability of these techniques in settings with more massive external legs, I will also briefly discuss the one-loop processes $pp \to HHH$ and $pp \to t\bar t H$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will outline the core ingredients of this computation: a basis-change algorithm in the vector space of rational functions based on correlations among multivariate residues; numerical sampling in number fields with non-Archimedean metrics (finite fields and $p$-adic numbers); the use of redundant spinor-helicity variables organised via polynomial quotient rings; and the role of primary decompositions in identifying allowed multivariate partial fraction decompositions. These methods not only yield efficient and stable results ready for phenomenological applications, but also expose structural features that we expect to generalise to more complex multi-loop amplitudes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards the complete NNLO BFKL Kernel</title>
      <link>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/refoct2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/refoct2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently there has been significant progress in understanding the
Regge limit in massless scattering amplitudes. In particular, all
the ingredients needed for the computation of the BFKL kernel at
NNLO have been determined in QCD, apart from the two-gluon
central emission vertex at one loop, which is known so far only
in maximally supersymmetric Yang-Mills theory. We present the
calculation of the next-to-multi-Regge-kinematic (NRMK) limit of
the six-gluon amplitude in QCD, from which this vertex can be
determined. Due to the complexity of the expressions for the
next-to-maximally-helicity-violating (NMHV) amplitude and the
high powers of spurious poles in the NMRK expansion parameter, we
use p-adic evaluation to obtain numerical samples for the leading
NMRK behaviour. We then employ analytic reconstruction techniques
to recover analytic results in a minimal set of independent
variables. In particular, allowed partial fraction depositions
are identified through nested p-adic limits near codimension-two
varieties.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytic One-Loop Amplitude for $gg \rightarrow HHH$</title>
      <link>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/hhh_workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/hhh_workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amplitude Reconstruction: Tools and Methods</title>
      <link>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/caravelmeeting2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 12:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/caravelmeeting2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loop amplitudes are essential ingredients in precision simulations of particle collisions at the LHC. Their computation poses both conceptual and computational challenges. A powerful and increasingly popular strategy to bypass intermediate bottlenecks in integrand reduction is to first evaluate amplitudes numerically over finite fields, and then recover their analytic form through analytic reconstruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will present two recent computations of fully analytic amplitudes obtained using this approach. The first is for the two-loop process $pp\rightarrow V(\rightarrow \bar\ell\ell)jj$ in the leading-color approximation (&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.10595&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;arXiv:2503.10595&lt;/a&gt;). In this case, we revisited a previous result (&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.07541&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;arXiv:2110.07541&lt;/a&gt;) and drastically simplified the amplitude from 1.4 GB to 1.9 MB, while also reducing the number of numerical samples from 1 million to 50 thousand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second computation is for the one-loop amplitude for $q\bar{q}\rightarrow t\bar{t}H$
(&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.19909&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;arXiv:2504.19909&lt;/a&gt;). This is the first time an amplitude has been reconstructed in the massive spinor-helicity formalism, which provides a minimal parametrisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will outline key aspects of both computations, focusing on the reconstruction technique, and in particular the role of minimal spinor-helicity parametrisations, the choice of efficient bases for master integral coefficients, and their representation via multivariate partial fractions. In this way, we uncover structural features of the amplitudes and provide numerically stable and efficient implementations suitable for phenomenological applications and further theoretical studies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytic Structure and Reconstruction in QCD: Two-Loop $pp \rightarrow Vjj$ and One-Loop $q\bar{q} \rightarrow t\bar{t}H$</title>
      <link>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/cernjune2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 12:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/cernjune2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loop amplitudes are essential ingredients in precision simulations of particle collisions at the LHC. Their computation poses both conceptual and computational challenges. A powerful and increasingly popular strategy to bypass intermediate bottlenecks in integrand reduction is to first evaluate amplitudes numerically over finite fields, and then recover their analytic form through analytic reconstruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will present two recent computations of fully analytic amplitudes obtained using this approach. The first is for the two-loop process $pp\rightarrow V(\rightarrow \bar\ell\ell)jj$ in the leading-color approximation (&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.10595&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;arXiv:2503.10595&lt;/a&gt;). In this case, we revisited a previous result (&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.07541&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;arXiv:2110.07541&lt;/a&gt;) and drastically simplified the amplitude from 1.4 GB to 1.9 MB, while also reducing the number of numerical samples from 1 million to 50 thousand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second computation is for the one-loop amplitude for $q\bar{q}\rightarrow t\bar{t}H$
(&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.19909&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;arXiv:2504.19909&lt;/a&gt;). This is the first time an amplitude has been reconstructed in the massive spinor-helicity formalism, which provides a minimal parametrisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will outline key aspects of both computations, focusing on the reconstruction technique, and in particular the role of minimal spinor-helicity parametrisations, the choice of efficient bases for master integral coefficients, and their representation via multivariate partial fractions. In this way, we uncover structural features of the amplitudes and provide numerically stable and efficient implementations suitable for phenomenological applications and further theoretical studies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytic Structure and Reconstruction in QCD: Two-Loop $pp \rightarrow Vjj$ and One-Loop $q\bar{q} \rightarrow t\bar{t}H$</title>
      <link>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/loopfest_may2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 12:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/loopfest_may2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We consider two-loop QCD corrections in the leading color approximation for the production of a heavy electroweak vector boson, $V=\{W^\pm,Z,\gamma^*\}$, in association with two light jets ($Vjj$) at hadron colliders. Leptonic decays of the electroweak boson are included at the amplitude level. We develop an approach that allows us to derive an analytic representation three orders of magnitude smaller than previously known results. This approach combines an improved choice of bases for rational coefficients, the construction of judiciously partial-fractioned ansätze, and iterative reconstruction in singular limits. We identify several recurring features of the amplitudes that we expect will facilitate analytic reconstruction and optimization of analytic representation for more complex amplitudes in the future. Finally, we provide an efficient and stable C++ numerical implementation of our results, ready for phenomenological applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compact Two-Loop QCD Corrections for $Vjj$ Production in Proton Collisions</title>
      <link>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/sm@lhc_apr2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 16:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/sm@lhc_apr2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We consider two-loop QCD corrections in the leading color approximation for the production of a heavy electroweak vector boson, $V=\{W^\pm,Z,\gamma^*\}$, in association with two light jets ($Vjj$) at hadron colliders. Leptonic decays of the electroweak boson are included at the amplitude level. We develop an approach that allows us to derive an analytic representation three orders of magnitude smaller than previously known results. This approach combines an improved choice of bases for rational coefficients, the construction of judiciously partial-fractioned ansätze, and iterative reconstruction in singular limits. We identify several recurring features of the amplitudes that we expect will facilitate analytic reconstruction and optimization of analytic representation for more complex amplitudes in the future. Finally, we provide an efficient and stable C++ numerical implementation of our results, ready for phenomenological applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two-Loop Five-Point Amplitudes in the Spinor Helicity Formalism</title>
      <link>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/ichep_jul2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/ichep_jul2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I present recent efforts to tame the algebraic complexity of two-loop five-point scattering amplitudes in the spinor helicity formalism. These amplitudes are required, for instance, to obtain next-to-next-to-leading order predictions for the production of three jets or of a massive vector boson with two jets at the Large Hadron Collider. I review the method of numerical generalized and the integrand decomposition technique employed to generate finite-field or p-adic samples of the amplitudes. I then focus on the study of the analytic properties of the rational coefficients and their reconstruction from said numerical samples. I show how to exploit correlations among codimension-one residues to simplify the calculation. I touch upon various interdisciplinary aspects, including elements of number theory, computational algebraic geometry, constraint programming, memoization, and GPU acceleration.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-Planar Two-Loop Amplitudes for Five-Parton Scattering</title>
      <link>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/loopslegs_apr2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/loopslegs_apr2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I present the recent calculation of the two-loop amplitudes required to obtain next-to-next-to-leading order predictions for three-jet production at the Large Hadron Collider. This calculation is performed in full color, that is including contributions from non-planar Feynman diagrams. I review the method of numerical generalized unitarity and the integrand decomposition technique employed to generate finite-field samples of the amplitude. I will then focus on the analytic reconstruction of the coefficient functions from said numerical samples. A novel algorithm, based on the correlation of codimension-one residues, helps tame the complexity of the calculation. Rescalings of the gluon amplitude, inspired by supersymmetry Ward identities, facilitate the computation of the quark amplitudes. I touch upon various interdisciplinary aspects of the computation, including elements of number theory, computational algebraic geometry, constraint programming, memoization, and GPU acceleration.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rational Functions of Scattering Amplitudes with Masses</title>
      <link>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/qcd_meets_ew_feb2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/qcd_meets_ew_feb2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-Planar Two-Loop Amplitudes for Five-Parton Scattering</title>
      <link>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/amlitudesmeeting_dec2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/amlitudesmeeting_dec2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I present the recent calculation of the two-loop amplitudes required to obtain next-to-next-to-leading order predictions for three-jet production at the Large Hadron Collider. This calculation is performed in full colour, that is including contributions from non-planar Feynman diagrams. I review the method of numerical generalized generalized and the integrand decomposition technique employed to generate finite-field samples of the amplitude. I will then focus on the analytic reconstruction of the coefficient functions from said numerical samples. A novel algorithm, based on the correlation of codimension-one residues, helps tame the complexity of the calculation. I touch upon various interdisciplinary aspects of the computation, including elements of number theory, computational algebraic geometry, constraint programming, memoization, and GPU acceleration.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathematical and Physical Structures of Rational Functions in Scattering Amplitudes</title>
      <link>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/mathemamplitudes_sept2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/mathemamplitudes_sept2023/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-planar two-loop QCD corrections to qq̅→γγγ: finite remainders in the spinor-helicity formalism</title>
      <link>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/loopfestxxi_june2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 14:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/loopfestxxi_june2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will present the computation of the NNLO double-virtual subleading-color corrections to the production of three photons at hadron colliders. I will briefly review the numerical generalized unitarity computation over finite fields performed with the C++ code Caravel, including updates that made this computation possible. I will then formulate the rational reconstruction problem for the finite remainders in spinor variables and obtain compact analytic expressions. Finally, I will show the effect of the subleading-color corrections on the hard functions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern Methods for the Computation of Scattering Amplitudes</title>
      <link>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/psi-ltp-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/psi-ltp-seminar/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytical Amplitudes from Numerical Exploration</title>
      <link>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/summer-meeting-july2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/summer-meeting-july2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconstruction of analytical amplitudes across loops, legs and theories</title>
      <link>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/ippp-internal-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/ippp-internal-seminar/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytical amplitudes from numerical evaluations</title>
      <link>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/qcd@lhc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/qcd@lhc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will present a new method (&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1904.04067&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/1904.04067&lt;/a&gt;) to generate analytic expressions for the integral coefficients of loop amplitudes using numerical evaluations only. We use high precision arithmetic to explore the singularity structure of the coefficients and decompose them into parts of manageable complexity. Each part is isolated by choosing an appropriate region of phase space, and reconstructed by solving a system of linear equations for the coefficients of a generic ansatz. To illustrate the usability of our method I will present sample computations for six-gluon one-loop integral coefficients and rational parts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From numerical to analytical amplitudes</title>
      <link>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/qcdmasterclass2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gdelaurentis.github.io/talk/qcdmasterclass2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generalised unitarity and on-shell recursion relations have led to the automation of numerical computations for high multiplicity NLO matrix elements, whereas analytical expression are often still too complicated to be determined. I will present a new method (arXiv:1904.04067) to generate such analytic expressions using numerical evaluations only. We use high precision arithmetic to explore the singularity structure of the coefficients and decompose them into parts of manageable complexity. Each part is isolated by choosing an appropriate region of phase space, and reconstructed by solving a system of linear equations for the coefficients of a generic ansatz. To illustrate the usability of our method I will present sample computations for six-gluon one-loop integral coefficients and rational parts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
